Geikojuban Violet Evergarden 2020
But it's so sudden, isn't it?
If Grandma isn't feeling well,
she should call us.
I'm sure Grandma didn't say anything
knowing that Mom was busy.
You know yourself, right?
Grandma is like that.
Daisy.
Are you blaming Mom for this?
Not. But I think Grandma wants
to see us more often.
I think he wants us to be by his side more.
Because Grandma loves Mom very much.
Your grandmother lost her parents when she was young.
Letter?
Grandma received the letter from your great-grandmother
after your great-grandmother died.
Grandma received a letter from the dead?
He told Doll to send him a letter...
...every birthday even after he died.
Dolls? Is there a letter writer doll?
Long ago, there was a man who invented a typewriter for his blind wife...
...and named the machine Automemory Puppet.
After that, the woman who worked as a letter writer was called Doll.
Letter writer?
They wrote a letter in someone's name?
Right. In the past many people could not read and write.
But now more and more people can read and write.
Telephones are also widespread....
Fewer people want to send letters,
and the job may no longer exist.
When someone wants to write a special letter...
... or difficulty in writing,
they will ask Doll for help.
Grandma took great care of the letter.
So.
Let's go back.
The patients are waiting for us.
Yes.
Let's go, Daisy.
I want to be here a little longer.
The funeral just finished. If the house
is empty, Grandma must be lonely, right?
Daisy ....
Mom just go home.
Mother always prioritizes work over family.
That ....
Mom always loves you and your grandma!
Let's take you to the station.
Daisy, after we're done with work,
we will come back again.
Grandma, I said another bad thing to Mother.
Even though I know very well how difficult Mother's work is.
"Ann, happy 8th birthday.
There may be many sad things,
and you may find it difficult.
But never give up.
Even if you're sad
and want to cry, but never forget....
Your mother always loved you, Ann."
"Ann, happy 10th birthday.
You must have grown up, huh.
But you must still like reading and dancing, right?
Are you bored...
...with puzzles and insects?
"Happy 18th birthday.
You've become a grown woman, yes.
Do you have a lover?
I can't give you love advice,
but I'm sure the person you choose...
... is a very amazing oarng. "
"Happy birthday, Ann.
You've lived for 20 years, haven't you!
Great!
Even though you're an adult,
You can still complain once in a while, really.
When you feel restless,
I'll always be here for you.
Ann.
I will always watch over you.
Ann."
Every year ....
He receives these letters every birthday?
Great-grandmother really cared about grandma, didn't she.
Newspaper snippets?
This guy ....
The person who wrote the letter...
... was the famous Doll at the time.
Once upon a time he wrote a love letter to the Princess.
And another time, he was asked to write lyrics...
... by a singer in the new opera.
Plus, he's also written stage scripts...
... for famous writers.
He worked at the Postal Company in Leiden....
But he left when he was 18,
and was never seen again.
The Doll's name is...
We found it from the Northeast battlefield.
He doesn't have a name.
Greetings!
Don't be rude!
He's still a kid.
Gil ....
He's not a kid.
He is a weapon.
Just a tool for war.
If so, may I give him a name?
Violet.
Your name is Violet.
When you grow up...
...you will surely become a woman as beautiful as your name.
You are not a tool,
but you would be a good
fit for the name.
Violet Evergarden.
Please come forward.
The author of this year's Hymn of the Sea will present this year's hymn to the Goddess of the Sea, Irma Fliech.
Hymn of the Sea.
That's very good, Violet.
I'm sure you wrote it aloud, yes, Violet-chan.
Yes.
It was different from ordinary letters.
The sea stretches endlessly,
inhabited by various sea creatures.
The place is so prosperous and beautiful.
But they are not like humans who
have achievements, positions, and personalities,
so I find it difficult to idolize him.
Well....
Okay! I'll be writing it next year!
Hey, hey, you have to be selected first
to write the Hymn of the Sea.
I will write a lot of letters from now on
and will be selected!
Yes, Violet?
Yes. Try to be elected.
Leave it to me.
Yes.
Violet Evergarden.
Mayor and Mayor.
Violet-chan, she is the Mayor of Leiden and his wife.
Nice to meet you.
If it's a client request,
we'll go anywhere.
Automemory Puppet Service,
I'm Violet Evergarden.
Amazing. You really look like a doll.
I already know very well about you.
Because it was I who suggested your name to write the Hymn of the Sea for the tradition of Thanksgiving to the Sea.
The love letter you wrote to the Flugel Kingdom, and the oath to King Damian,
all of them are so amazing just like you.
The oath for the coronation....
I only wrote down the dreams and aspirations of Damian who would become king.
You do call me amazing,
but I don't think that has anything to do with my writing,
Please don't misunderstand.
Violet-chan, in other words....
In other words, I respect you.
You've done enough as Doll,
but while you were still in the army,
you also saved Leidenschaftlich.
It wasn't me who saved this city.
It was because of the soldiers who joined the war.
But at the same time,
many lives lost.
Including me.
Therefore ...
... I am not a human to be worshipped.
Want to eat?
I want yakisoba.
Every now and then choose a different meal.
Yes.
Violet.
Erica-san.
Long time no see.
Whoa! You look good, yes.
Yes.
Director, long time no see.
Are you used to being
an assistant script writer?
You
helped the scriptwriter too, didn't you, Violet?
Yes.
After seeing the performance,
I introduced him to Erica-san.
I asked him to take me as his disciple.
I check his writing every day.
Although it was a bit difficult to type the script,
but it became a lesson for me.
Want yakisoba?
Hey, Benedict!
You're interrupting the conversation!
It's bad that you said that.
Want to tour the celebrations with us?
Sorry, I'm glad you took me,
but after this I have a rehearsal
for next month's performance.
You wrote it, Erica-san?
Yes. It's just a small show at City Hall, really.
Please come if you have free time.
Alright, I'll say goodbye first.
If you beg as hard as you can,
your feelings will come true, yes.
How about a request that wo
n't come true even though I strongly ask?
I said goodbye too.
I still have a lot of work.
You can take the day off today.
It's a celebration now.
No, this could get in the way of my work plans.
I'll just go back.
Higher ....
Higher?
Run ...
Just leave me.
Run!
I won't let you die!
Enough.
Stop it!
You have to stay alive.
Violet,
You must stay alive and free.
From the bottom of my heart, I...
... love you.
"To Major Gilbert,
Today, I think of you again.
Whatever I see and do,
I always think of you.
Even though time goes on,
and you keep walking away,
My memories with you are still vivid.
You were by my side and
taught me how to survive.
Then for me, you....
"I love you."
You said that to me.
Therefore, I am writing this letter again.
Hope this letter reaches you,
and my wish will come true."
Here's your change of three kohls.
Thank you very much.
It weighs 1.2 libre,
a total of 11 kohls.
Yes, with the CH Postal Company.
We will go anywhere according to the client's wishes.
Automemory Puppet Service,
I'm Doll Iris Cannary.
Yes, he is.
Sorry for waiting.
Too bad, the Doll you asked for is
already busy for the next three months.
How about with me?
I see.
Good. I'll put you
on the waiting list after three months.
Yes, true.
Thank you.
Iris,
Don't be annoyed with the client.
My attitude is invisible, right over the phone.
Your expression also shows through your voice.
Yes.
Besides, you also have a lot of work, right?
Not as much as you, Cattleya-san.
At this rate, I will continue to be number three.
Good work!
Ah, Director, good job!
This week must be busy, right?
Everyone, please go on vacation tomorrow.
I have a business trip this weekend.
You asked me to be the secretary of the Galdarik company agreement revision meeting, right?
That's right, yes.
I'm going to the Mayor's wife's party.
I will increase the number of my clients.
You all work seriously, huh....
Recently I started playing tennis,
maybe someone wants to accompany me.
Don't you have any sense of vigilance, Director?
We have to work hard now, otherwise...
...these letters will be obsolete because of that shitty machine.
Construction of the radio tower will be completed soon.
And after that,
telephone will be more and more widespread.
Right. A lot has changed, yes.
This postal company is also slowly changing.
One day this work will be obsolete.
Then Doll will also be abandoned and disappear.
That's why we have to work hard now!
So, are you going to the party, Violet?
Not me ....
I don't want to invite my rival!
Yes I agree.
I also have other plans.
Young!
Ouch! Reply longer, please!
It might be fun to fight women,
but I'm against you
Everyone is busy.
Even Violet-chan doesn't want to accompany me.
No problem, right?
Rarely did he want to go out.
Ah, but if she's here, it
's easy for us to attract other women too.
Many people ask me
while delivering letters,
"You're from the CH Postal Company?"
"Introduce me to Violet, please!"
Don't use Violet-chan for your lecherous motives!
But....
Where did he go, huh?
You're exaggerating, huh.
Captain.
So you, huh? The person who always brings
flowers on every anniversary of my mother's death.
I should have come tomorrow,
but other family members will also be here.
Is that bothersome?
Not.
But....
You don't have to bother coming here.
Now is your day off.
In fact, I was able to come because I was on vacation.
To replace him?
I am not the Major's representative.
I came of my own free will.
It's been a long time since the war ended.
You already know, right?
Forget about Gilbert.
I have a hard time forgetting it.
I can't forget it as long as I'm alive.
Hey!
Violet.
Wrong! It's not violets,
but pansies.
So.
You know very well, yes.
Even though I can't see him anymore....
It's hard to forget, huh.
Pitaku ....
Yes, with CH Postal Company--
Is there Doll there?
Me too Doll.
Is it true? I want to ask something.
Can you come here?
Our company is closed today.
Uh? Impossible!
Oh, I see.
Sorry to be presumptuous, but your voice still sounds quite young.
Do you have to know my age to write a letter?
Doll will go wherever the client wants, right?
Is that a lie?
No, it's not a lie.
Then come!
Who?
I am Doll from CH Postal Company.
Oh, please come in.
Excuse me.
Nice to meet you.
We will go anywhere according to client's request.
Automemory Puppet Service,
I'm Violet Evergarden.
Wow, you really came, huh.
Because you asked for it.
You look young, are
you sure?
I will try.
Yurith!
Brother, here we come!
We're in, yeah!
Wait a minute!
Hide quickly!
Hurry up!
Brother!
Yurith, is anyone coming?
Nothing.
Is it true?
Mother heard a voice talking.
How is your condition?
Don't ask the same thing every day.
Are you alright?
If I was okay,
I wouldn't be here.
Sorry.
Brother....
I'll read you a picture book!
Boring picture books.
He is not feeling well.
Not feeling unwell anymore
I've had surgery three times and been hospitalized for a year.
Oh yes, Yurith, he said Ryuka wanted to see you.
He said he wanted to meet you.
Tell me not to come.
Why? You guys are very close, right?
Never mind!
What is this?
Worn--
Don't touch it, idiot!
It was a deposit from the person who
visited the next room.
I am sleepy!
Sorry. We'll go for a walk first.
Right. You better rest.
We will come again later.
Sorry.
Can I go out now?
Can you tell me why I have to hide?
Young master?
Just call Yurith.
All right, Mr Yurith.
I want to keep it a secret from my family.
You mean your letter?
Yes.
I want to write a letter to them.
I want them to read it
after I die.
So, I want you to keep it for a while.
Not immediately given.
Good.
You know what I mean?
Can you do it?
Does not matter.
We've also received
similar requests before.
I am writing a letter to a mother to
her daughter who is a little younger than you.
Even after Mother died, we sent it for 50 years every daughter's birthday.
50 years?
On and on?
Yes.
Even now, the letter is still sent
every time it's his birthday.
Sorry,
but I didn't ask for such a thing.
I'll just ask you to write
as much as the money in the tin.
So, how many letters can you write?
For each letter, about 20 letters.
20 letters?
“Mother, take care of yourself, Yurith.”
It's too short!
I myself can write that short!
I want the letter to cheer up
my family after reading it.
I want a letter like that!
Mister Yurith, that was just a simple calculation.
But our company has a discount for small children.
So, we can accept your request and write the letter you want with the money in this tin.
Are you serious?
I am serious.
Don't just say it!
I'm not just talking.
For the sake of carrying out
my duties, I was given special provisions for emergencies.
My special terms.
I do not understand,
but i leave it to you!
I agree!
Let's start!
Your hand....
I lost my hand in the war.
Several years ago, I was also
hospitalized.
Can you write letters?
It took me a long time to get used to this prosthetic hand.
But now it's no problem.
So, I can also do this.
You're attractive, yes.
Usually everyone asks me how I'm doing
and tells me to rest.
But you're different, huh.
What do you mean different?
For example, don't worry about me, feel sorry for me,
or be too much for me.
Anyway, I'm fed up with it.
Good.
I will get those three things out of my mind.
You are interesting, yes.
Young ....
Write me a letter.
For my father.
Father?
Yes! My father went to war.
He went to the country of Leidenschaftlich.
He said he'd be right back
but he still hasn't come back!
So, I want to tell Dad
that me, my sister, and Mom are doing well!
You want to write my letter?
Let's take Violet-chan to eat?
Ah, then, let's go to that restaurant.
The restaurant
Violet went to when she first came here.
you....
Captain Dietfried.
Lieutenant Colonel Hodgins.
No, you're a Director now, aren't you.
I had forgotten that the war was long over.
Do you have any need?
Nothing.
Violet ....
Captain.
Forgive my impudence.
It is okay.
I brought this.
That's my ribbon....
You came to return it?
I saw this ribbon fall.
What place did Violet-chan go to….
Funeral.
I visited the grave of Major Gilbert's mother.
Captain, thank you very much.
Fine.
Put our things down and go eat!
Right.
Come with you too, Violet-chan.
Yes.
Hey!
I want to throw away the ship I own.
Ship?
Yes.
It was the ship he used to ride when he was little.
There were toys, and books that my sister often reads.
If there's anything you want....
May I have it?
But it's junk.
I will be there!
I will go wherever the ship is docked!
I didn't know you went
to his funeral every month.
Do I have to report it?
Ah no.
You don't have to.
It is your privacy.
So, about the ship....
I will report when I want to visit it.
I told you not to.
Violet-chan, want to go with me?
No need. You can get rid of your feelings of anxiety, pity,
and excess.
No problem he said.
Noisy!
You shut up and just eat!
As Violet said.
You can't always worry about him.
Of course I was worried about him.
Moreover, Dietfried has entered the
gap in Violet-chan's heart.
It was possible that he was
the perfect match for Violet.
Because they could share memories
with Major Gilbert.
That person took Violet-chan from the orphanage...
... and make it a tool for war.
Was that why he couldn't approach Violet?
Even though it's changed now?
Did they both
treat each other's wounds?
Is that a bad thing?
Even now, Violet still had feelings
for Major Gilbert.
If left unchecked, I'm afraid he'll be crushed by his own feelings.
But if with Captain....
He may be able to give us a spirit
that we cannot give.
Tch, if I have children someday, I
'd rather be a boy.
I can't stand women.
This is a book he reads seriously.
He often played with Dad too.
Is this Major's too?
No, it's mine.
Sorry.
You don't have to be so stiff.
Good.
You two used to go out to sea
on this ship when you were little, didn't you?
Yes.
Our father invited us.
Our father is a soldier.
But somehow he likes the sea.
And that's why I became the navy.
This is our family flower.
What do you mean?
What did you say?
Dad just wanted to show that, right?
For us to grow up to be like Dad, right?
brother.
You want to make us understand
that it's our only option, right?
Brother!
I want to say that
the Bouganvillea family can only be soldiers, right?
Dad, stop it! Don't hit Bro!
I will be a soldier!
I will be like Daddy!
Because I was so rebellious to Daddy,
maybe Gil can only do what Dad wants.
Because of my fault, my sister's life became restricted.
I couldn't even approach him
because my behavior was unforgivable.
I don't have a brother, so I don't understand.
But because he is close to you,
you feel mixed emotions.
I can understand it a little.
Can you understand human feelings?
No, I didn't mean to offend you.
I see.
May I keep this book and board game?
Yes.
Let's get out?
You are okay?
Thank you very much.
We're both missing a lot, huh.
I'm sorry for earlier.
When I said you couldn't see him anymore
or told you to forget him.
Even I can't forget it.
In the end, she is still my sister.
Yes.
If we meet again,
I want to apologize and talk about something.
Yes.
Next for my sister.
Even so, what should I write for my sister?
Shion is still five years old.
How about writing about how you felt when he was born?
Yes.
I was happy when he was born.
It's like freshly baked bread, it's warm and soft.
But....
Slowly you feel he grabs the attention
of parents from you.
Yes.
They often praise and
joke with your sister?
Yes, true.
But, when he chases you look cute?
Why do you understand?
It's all just from the stories I've heard.
If so, write that down and add this.
Please live a happier life for me.
Then,
be kind to Mom and Dad for me too.
Thank you Mom and Dad's love for me too.
Actually you want to get a lot of affection....
As far as I understand, you are not speaking from the bottom of your heart.
You know everything, don't you?
I have written many letters, so I understand every sentence, attitude, feeling has a secret meaning.
And I understand that everything visible
to the eye is not everything.
But your true feelings....
You have to share it
so that other people know.
Is this enough?
Thank you.
All right, I'll take care of your three letters.
Yes.
Leave it to them when I die, okay?
I'll have the hospital
notify the post office too.
Yes.
Hey, can you promise pinky?
Pinky promise?
Right, we connect our little finger.
Then swear to each other to keep their promises.
Thank you.
Your fingers are cold, yes.
I even understand even wearing gloves.
Before winter comes,
I'm sure I'm cold too.
Even so, I'm sure the letter you left
will warm the hearts of your family.
I promise to hand over the letter.
My job is done.
Wait!
There's one more letter I want to ask you.
For Mr. Ryuka?
I heard it while I was under the bed.
Yes.
It's best if you say that straight away
while you can.
Oh, I see?
Yes.
Because I can't ask
or say anything anymore.
To whom?
To people who love me.
Is that person dead?
I'm sure he's still alive somewhere.
What do you want to tell him?
That I have a little understand the meaning
of the words "I love you" from him.
That is all?
I wanted Ryuka to come visit me,
but I forbade him.
I've been close to Ryuka since I was little.
We always play together.
But my legs and arms are getting thinner....
And I don't want him to see me like this.
I will write that feeling down in a letter.
The cost....
Mr Yurith!
I called the nurse!
We will write to Mr. Ryuka another time.
Sorry.
It is okay.
All these letters don't have addresses, do they?
I received it from Rolan and the old man.
They want unaddressed mail
returned.
Then? Why are you asking for my help?
Young people today do not want to work overtime,
and I've been working this hard,
You should make me Deputy Director, okay?
Then go to accounting school!
A person who cannot read the
Annual Journal cannot become a Deputy Director.
I'm starting to see hope!
Maybe I should try to study it a bit.
This....
Ah, all the letters on this shelf are still pretty new.
This writing ....
What is wrong?
It is nothing.
The return address is from Ecatel Island.
That place was a former colony of
the Galdaric Empire, right?
But they were free after the war ended, huh?
What do you need with me, Director?
A few days ago ....
You mean about Doll from your company?
Did he say something?
Not.
Take it easy. After he visited my ship,
I sent him home because the Director was worried about him.
Even though he said he would report when he wanted to leave.
You're not the guardian.
You have no right to limit it.
you....
You don't deserve to say it!
Sorry.
I am wrong.
I can only say it like that.
I didn't come here today
to ask about Violet-chan.
This....
Can you investigate?
Director ....
Sorry to bother you at night.
I want to talk to you.
What is wrong?
It's still not certain....
Maybe I'm wrong....
About Major Gilbert?
Yes.
Do you know something?
Do you know anything about Major Gilbert?
So, what now?
Maybe I'm wrong, but I'll check.
Good!
Leave the work to us!
Violet, are you okay?
Is it ok....
Is it okay if I see Major Gilbert?
Is it okay?
Time has passed so long,
does Major still remember me?
Vi-Violet ....
What should I say first
when I see him?
What about the current conditions?
Or about my feelings?
Can I convey it well?
Will he be disgusted with me?
Violet.
It's very far away, isn't it?
How about you write a letter
until you get there?
We're home, Daisy!
Sorry we came home late.
Daisy?
"I'm going to Leiden for a while."
The postal company where he worked merged with other companies to become a national company.
The original building has become a museum.
After he stopped working here,
where did he go?
Enjoy your time here.
Sorry, I didn't realize you were there.
It is okay.
If you have any questions, just ask me.
Yes.
Actually, I used to
be a receptionist here too.
Oh, I see?
Yes.
Anu, about this cap....
This is a stamp that exists only on Ecatel Island.
Ecatell Island....
Anu, you said
earlier , you used to work here, huh?
Yes.
Blessed sea.
The sea that unites the world.
Seagulls fly above you.
Fish swim in you.
The rocks are hiding beneath you.
You receive the light,
and you take care of life.
You are full of love,
and always provide comfort...
... until the end.
You knit the past, present,
and future.
We surrender our bodies to you.
Actually this is intended to
express gratitude to the sea.
But now it is a memorial to the death of
someone who has died
Nobody's coming back here, huh.
The only people living on this island are the elderly, women, and children.
We feel guilty that they
died on the battlefield, not at sea.
My father and the others
were killed by the Leiden soldiers, right?
It's better if all Leiden people die.
The reading of the greeting was
from the Leiden Thanksgiving Festival.
Said it was written by the famous Doll.
Her name is Violet Evergarden.
Everyone, let's eat!
Let's go.
Come on!
Master, I love you!
Let's go quickly!
Major Gilbert, long time no see.
As long as we don't meet,
I think of you every day.
And may my prayers be heard, my wishes come true, and may meet you one day.
Violet-chan, can you wait here a moment?
I want to come too.
Even though Gilbert is right here,
we don't know how he is now.
So....
It is okay!
Even if you don't mind....
But what about him?
Looks like he's not using his real name here.
This is a small island.
He definitely didn't want rumors to appear here.
You'll be waiting here, right?
Yes.
If I get to meet Major Gilbert,
I'll be waiting any time.
We're new to the island, can
you go around?
Good.
I don't know who the uncle is.
Good afternoon!
whose father are you?
Oh, no....
Who is it, then?
Suspicious.
I'm from the postal company.
So, you came to deliver the mail, huh?
That's it....
Oh yes, I gave you something good!
He was shocked!
Let us go home!
My soul is not strong enough to face them.
Ma'am who are you?
Me ....
From the postal company?
Yes, true.
I knew it!
I give you a good thing!
This!
Insect?
What is a praying mantis?
Aren't you surprised?
One front leg is missing.
Yes, it's the same with Mr. Gilbert.
Did the teacher lose
his right eye too?
You know that right?
He's your teacher, right?
Really!
Is your teacher okay?
Yes! Even though he doesn't have a right hand,
he can lift his body with his left!
Running fast too, huh!
Yes, he is very fast!
Yes?
Can....
Can you tell us more about your teacher?
Can you do it!
He's a very good teacher!
Who?
Please come in.
If there's something you don't understand--
I really didn't expect it.
You're still alive, Gilbert.
Here, people call me Gilbel.
So.
Sorry I came suddenly.
How do you know this place?
You wrote a letter to a child, right?
Letters whose address is not clear
will be returned to the post office.
When I checked the letters
before they were returned to the sender,
I happened to see the letter.
Why are you here too?
After the war,
I woke up in a hospital bed.
'Cause I don't have an ID,
I was admitted to a religious hospital.
After I helped the hospital,
I did not return to my country,
but wandered here and there.
I came here a year ago.
While I was writing letters to the children.
I became their teacher.
You don't have to worry about it.
Did you know that Violet-chan is still alive?
Yes.
Then why don't you come see him?
Violet-chan ....
He's always waiting for you!
I have made him suffer!
I better not be by his side.
He came.
I told him to wait outside.
Do you know how much he misses you?
I won't meet him
Gilbert.
I won't see him again.
you....
He has died.
Gilbert Bougainvillea has died.
Everyone thinks so.
And they should have accepted my death
with time.
So let me live a different life.
Gilbert--
Now...
It is grape harvest time.
After this, I will help them.
All the men of this island went to war,
and no one came back.
Hodgins, I beg you.
Go home.
Please think again.
Are you ...
... hate me?
I don't know what your question means.
Did I do something wrong?
If there is an error, I will correct it.
Please just say it.
Not.
What's wrong is that I...
...that calls you not a tool,
but instead I use you as a tool.
You deserve to use me!
I am the Major's weapon!
We are in a corner.
What should we do?
Major, give orders!
Director!
That's right Major!
He really is Major.
I heard it from the children.
You've met the Major, right?
Yes.
Apart from the injuries to his right hand and eye,
he's fine, right?
Then, I can meet him, right?
He said he didn't want to see him.
Is he still busy at work?
If so, I'll wait until he's done.
It is not like that.
Then, until the evening....
Violet-chan!
How about tommorow?
That is true.
I'll talk to him again tomorrow.
He has to meet you.
What do you mean Major not can't see me,
but doesn't want to see me?
Why?
I can't put
it into words , but he said it was for the best.
That is not true!
Me ....
Violet-chan ....
Violet-chan!
Once that's done, we can haul the grapes
up more easily, huh.
You're very helpful.
Looks like it's going to rain heavily.
Higher!
I've found him.
Higher.
Higher ....
Higher!
I'm sorry to have
bothered getting to your house.
Higher,
If you're still alive,
why don't you call me?
Why don't you want to see me?
I want to meet you.
I want to continue
our last conversation.
I already understand a little what you mean to love me.
Come home....
Go home.
I will wait until I can meet you.
I will wait here.
I don't need you now.
Besides, if you're here, I'm reminded.
That I have brought your young self to the battlefield.
You listened to my orders
and lost both your hands....
You regret it, yes.
My existence only makes you suffer, huh.
Now I understand your feelings.
Although not completely
but i got it.
You stupid!
Please use this.
Thank you.
Only this place allowed us to stay.
There is no accommodation here.
That's because it's a small island.
Violet-chan, this lighthouse is also
a post office.
So.
It's time for this flower to bloom again, huh.
The prince's eyes were as blue as sapphire.
The sword on his waist was as bright as a red ruby.
You've read well, haven't you, Violet.
Don't separate from me.
Stay with me, Violet.
Yes.
You two are from the postal company in Leiden?
Oh, yes.
Was that woman Violet Evergarden?
There's a call from the hospital for the postal company.
He said the man named Yurith was in a coma.
Yurith?
Who is she?
He is ...
... my client.
Leave it to them when I die, okay?
Yes.
I will go home.
Uh?
I have to go back to Leiden.
Violet-chan!
You want to come back in the middle of this storm?
At least wait until morning
to board the ship.
You said you wanted to meet Gilbert, right?
I want to meet him.
I want to meet him!
But.
I promised her pinky.
I already made a promise with Mister Yurith.
Besides, he still hadn't written his last letter.
But even if you hurry,
you'll be there in three days.
Faster!
I know!
Just now, Benedict and Iris
went to the hospital with the letter.
Yes.
Excuse me.
Yurith, Doll has come.
There's a letter you want to write, right?
Violet?
I'm Iris who came in her place.
Violet was far away from here.
Finally he can meet the person he loves.
That person has expressed his feelings?
Right.
He's still alive, yes.
Thank God.
I've heard from Violet.
You want to write a letter to Ryuka-kun, right?
Yes.
What should I write?
Yurith!
Yurith, it's fine now.
Yes, please connect to it!
Yurith-kun, ini Ryuka-kun ..
What should I do?
Say hello.
Yurith!
Hello?
Ryuka?
I am here!
I have forbidden you to visit me,
and I said I didn't want to see you.
Sorry... I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
I was sad when you said you didn't want to see me,
but I'm sure it's the best in your opinion.
So, I held back.
But I couldn't help myself
and repeatedly went to the hospital.
Then I slightly saw your face from the window.
Sorry, I said something bad.
It is okay.
I'm not angry at all, really.
Yurith.
We're friends forever, right?
From now on, let's be friends forever, shall we?
Yes.
Thank God.
Thank you.
Even those disgusting machines can be useful, yes.
Yurith!
He did not have time to write the letter.
But she managed to talk to Ryuka-kun one last time over the phone,
and he said he managed to convey his feelings.
He manages to apologize and thank her.
Then the letter you wrote for him
has been handed over to his family.
"Mom, Mom's pancakes taste good.
Would you be happy
if I ate more vegetables?
Father,
I really like it when we go
camping and fishing.
I am happy that I was born to be a father and mother's child.
I love you all.
From Yurith."
There is a letter for the sister too.
I?
"Shion,
sorry for always scolding and bullying you, yes.
But I was so happy when you were born.
Thank you for making me
a big sister.
Please live happily for me.
And take care of Mom and Dad for me too,
draw near to them, and treat them well.
To my dear sister...
...from your sister."
Brother, thank you!
I am happy!
Mom and Dad are happy too, right?
Yes.
Right.
Thank you, Yuri.
Said Yurith glad you managed to
meet the person you care about.
In the morning, let's visit him again.
If he doesn't come out, I'll break down the door...
...and hit him.
Not.
If you want to hit the Major, let me do it.
He saw--
I am joking.
I will return to the postal company
by ship tomorrow.
Uh?
I'll write a letter once I get there,
my work has piled up.
Violet.
Major is still alive.
I don't think I'll ever see him again.
Can only hear his voice....
That ...
...is enough for me.
Let's try.
He's coming!
Great.
Now it really gets easier with this tool, huh.
Uncle and Ma'am from the postal company!
Uncle?
The teacher created this machine!
Great!
Great right?
Yes.
Could you please hand this over to your teacher?
Good. I'll definitely give it up!
Drugs!
You don't have to carry this burden alone.
Well about the young men who
never return to this island,
or the number of people who died in the war,
maybe it's our fault too.
We will prosper if we go to war,
that's what everyone thinks.
I thought the Leidenscheftlish people hated us too.
But everyone is hurt.
All.
If there's a place for you to return,
you better come back.
Not.
I'll stay here.
Here forever.
You want to save us?
Me!
You've finally chosen your path on this island, haven't you?
This is indeed a great place.
brother.
You live well here,
but you didn't come
to your mother's funeral, did you?
Different from me, you are loved by him.
Sorry.
Well, Violet has come
to Mother's funeral on your behalf.
In fact, he still goes to Mother's grave every month.
When I see you again,
I want to apologize.
But now I want to put you in a sack...
...and get you out in front of Violet!
I shouldn't have accepted it at the time.
If so, what do you really want?
I wanted to give
her young self some good times.
Or let him like cute things.
I want to let her
heart beat with beautiful things.
I just wanted to make her experience those moments.
But....
That's for you.
Read it.
"To Major Gilbert,
sorry for suddenly coming to bother you.
This is the last letter I wrote to you.
The reason I'm still alive now...
... and can think of someone,
is your blessing.
Thank you for accepting me.
Has read a book to me,
taught me about letters
and many other things,
Thank you very much.
Has bought me a brooch,
Always... always by my side,
Thank you very much.
From the bottom of my heart...
Thank you for loving me.
And thanks to you saying love to me,
it has been the guide of my life.
And because I understand love,
I want to convey my love.
Higher,
Thank you very much.
Thank you ...
...for this long."
Anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is the guide
ichiwa no tori ga naite iru
Seekor burung pun berkicau
People have a hard time being
honest with their feelings, don't they?
namae no nai sora ni watashi wo sagashite
Mencari diriku di langit tanpa bernama
yasashisa de ami tsuzuketa I
keep going with the knitting of kindness
I will inherit the Bougainvillea family.
yurikago de asu e yukou
Towards the future in a cage
You go and be free.
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
So that it's sunny or rainy
anata wo mamoru tame ni
Kubisa melindungimu
Go.
kakegae no nai takaramono
Harta karun yang tak tergantikan
namae no nai hana wa shizuka ni nemuru yo
Bunga tanpa nama perlahan mulai tertidur
Violet!
Higher ....
sazukerareta tsubasa wo habatakasete I
flap the wings I have received
Gilbert.
tobu koto wo yamenai to yakusoku shiyou
Let's promise to keep flying
hitori ja nai
You're not alone
Higher!
Violet!
negai wa hitotsu dake anata no
shiawase Harapanku hanya satu, yaitu kebahagiaanmu
yasashisa de ami tsuzuketa I
keep going with the knitting of kindness
yurikago de asu e yukou
Towards the future in a cage
hare no hi mo ame no hi ni mo
So that it's sunny or rainy
anata wo mamoru tame ni
Kubisa melindungimu
Anata no koe ga michishirube
Your voice is the guide
Higher ....
Violet, I am neither your master nor your boss anymore.
I have hurt you.
I'm not the man you think.
I am neither a great master nor
a great man.
I believe I don't deserve you.
Even so ....
Even now... I...
... love you.
Me ....
I want to be with you, Violet.
Higher ....
Me ...
Violet, don't cry.
Look, I'm about to cry too.
I want to wipe your tears.
Please, raise your head.
Me ....
Higher ....
I love you, Violet.
I've always wanted to be like this.
After he finished
all his work,
he left the postal company where he worked.
And he said he was going to
the post office of the island's lighthouse.
But it looks like the post office
has been moved to a city street.
After the phone is created,
Doll profession has been considered ancient.
Maybe he helped everyone
write letters here.
If not ....
This stamp is only sold on this island,
and produced by the CH Postal Foundation.
The number of letters that come out of this island
is the highest every year.
At that time there was a profession called Doll.
And on this island there is also a famous Doll.
His name....
Violet Evergarden.
My grandmother also received a letter
written by him.
If I can't put it into words,
maybe I can express it by letter.
I also want to convey my sincere feelings.
The person I want to convey....
Only now is the time.
Father,
Mother,
Thank you.
I love you all
Hana wa yagate tsuchi ni kaeri mebuite yuku
One day the flowers will surely return to the ground and sprout again
Arata na wakaba wo sodatete iku no deshou
Then it will grow new leaves, right?
Soredemo aishita hibi wa kienai
Even so the day I love will never go away
Kaerou ka kaerou yo
Let's go home, let's go home
Sutesaru mono nante nai
There is nothing to throw away
Yorokobi kanashimi subete ni tayutai
Happiness and sadness, I want to feel it all
Tada tada tada anata to ikite yuku
Just, just, I just want to live with you
Ame wa agari kumo wa nagare tsugi no machi e The
cloud after the rain stops will surely go to the next city
Ayamachi wa iroasenu mama nokoru no deshou
But will mistakes never go away?
Soredemo watashi wa aruite yuku
Even so I will keep going
Hanasou ka hanasou yo
Let's talk, let's talk
Furikaeru kotoba yori mo
Daripada membicarakan masa lalu
arigato aishiteru koe no tayori kasanete
Like "thank you," and "I love you" at the same time
Tada tada tada anata to ikite yuku
Just, just, I just want to live with you